Hui Liang (Leo)

Software Engineer, Auckland, Work Visa

I am a capable IT professional person with more than 12 years of extensive experience in the full-cycle of software testing&development, including requirements analysis, software implementation, integration & testing, troubleshooting and maintenance by using multiple programming languages as well as testing tools in Windows, Linux, Embedded OS, Web and mobile development environments. I was involved deeply in Scrum & Agile development cycle since 2009 until now, which helped me obtain practical skills including Continuous Integration&Delivery, Exploratory Testing, Test Driven Development, Peer Review etc as well as tools like Jira, Git, Gerrit, SVN, Jenkins etc. I also gained many management skills by taking roles such as project coordinator, fault coordinator and Scrum Master (Team Leader). I'm a person who can be self-motivated and positive, and is a good team player because I always communicate with others openly and timely, and helpful to other team members.

Experience

2014.11 – 2017.11 Software Engineer, Specification Engineer

Nokia, Radio Network Business Group, China

I do software specification work for Nokia Radio Network related products BTS Mediator(**BTSMED**), and as both developer and tester for one company internal-usage website – **Meetup**. Meetup is a Node.JS based website and was used by more than 4000 users for technical events post and management.

Main responsibilities:

- o Deliver software code and test features for 'Meetup'
- o Software requirement specification for BTSMED

Activities:

- o Meetup:
 - Used languages&framework, scripts and DB: JS/Node.js/React/Redux/JQuery/Bootstrap/HTML/CSS/MySQL
 - Perform unit test by Mocha/supertest.
 - Designed some RESTful API. And all data is in JSON format.
 - Used Robot framework and Selenium library to perform automatic web testing.

o BTSMED:

- Do BTSMED software User Case/Scenario specification
- Approve BTSMED acceptance cases, and ensure that test cases are traceable back to product requirements



Personal Info

Phone

021 2357623

E-mail

13905538@qq.com

Date of birth

1980-11-10

Skillset

Robot	Selenium
Framework	
CI	CD
Jenkins	Hudson
TCP/IP/HTTP	HTML&
/UDP	CSS
React	Redux
Python	С
Javascript/N	jQuery
ode.js	
Ajax	SQLServer
MySQL	Sybase
Sails,Ngix,	Linux /
Apache	Ubuntu
Agile	Scrum
Git, SVN,	Gitlab
Gerrit	
Cloud,	Docker
VMWare	

2006.06 – 2014.10 Software Engineer, Scrum Master

Nokia, Radio Network Business Group, China

I am a software engineer of Nokia, and participate in Nokia Radio Network related products mainly for Radio Network Controller (RNC) and LTE Base Station, which is based on Linux Embedded OS.

Main responsibilities:

o Deliver software code and test features in functional (most of time) as well as non-functional level.

Activities:

- o Used languages and scripts: Robot Framework&Python/Linux Shell/C
- o Issues/bugs reporting, troubleshooting and fix verification.
- o Maintenance for automatic testing cases and scripts.
- o Test plan and test report writing
- o Integrate test cases into Continuous Integration framework
- o Coordinate cross team/inside team cooperative activities, and mentor junior colleagues.

Achievement:

- o Was ever one of excellent 'bug hunters' in the development unit (2010-2011). Find more software bugs and low leaking ratio to upper testing level.
- o Applied automation testing tools such as Robot framework and libraries. Almost 100% test automation ratio. BDD and TDD concept both applied in the project.
- o One of founders for Continuous Integration Framework, and integrated more than 2000 Functional Test Cases in 3 months.
- o Used bug management system like Jira, Pronto (Nokia privately owned) and Confluence.

2005.04 – 2006.06 Software Engineer

Hundsun Electronics, Financial Software Product Line, China

I'm a software engineer of Hundsun Enterprise Fund Management System and then be a Resident Engineer for many roll-out customers. This fund management system was developed for biggest banks and enterprises in China.

Main responsibilities:

o End-to-End responsible for developing and testing important software features e.g. cash transfer, cash sweep, balance inquiry, enterprise banking account management.

Activities:

- o Used languages and scripts: Linux &C/Delphi
- o Requirements Analysis, Software Design and Implementation.
- o End to end System Integration in lab, customer site roll-out and acceptance testing.
- o Technical Support, issue troubleshooting and pre-sale support.
- o Database maintenance based on Sybase and MSSQL Server; DB stored procedure scripting.

Education and Continuous Personal Development

2002.09 – 2005.01 Zhejiang University, China, Software Engineering, Master

1998.09 – 2002.07 Yunnan University, China, Communication Engineering, Bachelor

CPD Activities	2005	Technical Lecture	Sybase
(2005 - Now)	2008	Workshop	Test Automation
	2012	Workshop	Git & Gerrit
	2011	Workshop	Continuous Integration Framework
	2015	Online Training	Agile software testing
	2010	Workshop	Exploratory Testing
	2010	Classroom Training	Overview of IP and Ethernet Technology
	2011	Classroom Training	TCP/IP
	2012	Workshop	Root Cause Analysis and Escaped Defects
			Analysis for SW and HW
	2012	Online Training	ISTQB
	2012/2013/2016	Online Training	I Own Quality
	2013	Workshop	Lean Six Sigma for Beginners
	2014	Online Training	General Nokia Cloud introduction
	2012	Technical Lecture	Python Basic
	2016	Discussion Group	Javascript/React/Redux/Node.js
	2008	Classroom Training	Scrum & Agile development
	2009	Classroom Training	Certified Scrum Master training
	2007/2015	Workshop	Design Failure Mode & Effects Analysis
	2013	Technical Lecture	Linux Multi-Thread Programming
	2017	Online Training	Design for Security